{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The devices that provide the means for a computer to communicate with the user or other computers are referred to as:", "opta": "CPU", "optb": "ALU", "optc": "I/O", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The software used to drive microprocessor-based systems is called:", "opta": "assembly language", "optb": "firmware", "optc": "machine language code", "optd": "BASIC interpreter instructions", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The circuits in the 8085A that provide the arithmetic and logic functions are called the:", "opta": "CPU", "optb": "ALU", "optc": "I/O", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many buses are connected as part of the 8085A microprocessor?", "opta": "2", "optb": "3", "optc": "5", "optd": "8", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ________ ensures that only one IC is active at a time to avoid a bus conflict caused by two ICs writing different data to the same bus.", "opta": "control bus", "optb": "control instructions", "optc": "address decoder", "optd": "CPU", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many bits are used in the data bus?", "opta": "7", "optb": "8", "optc": "9", "optd": "16", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The items that you can physically touch in a computer system are called:", "opta": "software", "optb": "firmware", "optc": "hardware", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Single-bit indicators that may be set or cleared to show the results of logical or arithmetic operations are the:", "opta": "flags", "optb": "registers", "optc": "monitors", "optd": "decisions", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When referring to instruction words, a mnemonic is:", "opta": "a short abbreviation for the operand address", "optb": "a short abbreviation for the operation to be performed", "optc": "a short abbreviation for the data word stored at the operand address", "optd": "shorthand for machine language", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The technique of assigning a memory address to each I/O device in the computer system is called:", "opta": "memory-mapped I/O", "optb": "ported I/O", "optc": "dedicated I/O", "optd": "wired I/O", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When was the first 8-bit microprocessor introduced?", "opta": "1969", "optb": "1974", "optc": "1979", "optd": "1985", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of circuit is used at the interface point of an output port?", "opta": "decoder", "optb": "latch", "optc": "tristate buffer", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "I/O mapped systems identify their input/output devices by giving them a(n) ________.", "opta": "8-bit port number", "optb": "16-bit port number", "optc": "8-bit buffer number", "optd": "8-bit instruction", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of circuit is used at the interface point of an input port?", "opta": "decoder", "optb": "latch", "optc": "tristate buffer", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The register in the 8085A that is used to keep track of the memory address of the next op-code to be run in the program is the:", "opta": "stack pointer", "optb": "program counter", "optc": "instruction pointer", "optd": "accumulator", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The control bus and memories share a bidirectional bus in a typical microprocessor system.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "All computer programs for a machine are called:", "opta": "software", "optb": "firmware", "optc": "hardware", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The 8085A is a(n):", "opta": "16-bit parallel CPU", "optb": "8-bit serial CPU", "optc": "8-bit parallel CPU", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Because microprocessor CPUs do not understand mnemonics as they are, they have to be converted to ________.", "opta": "hexadecimal machine code", "optb": "binary machine code", "optc": "assembly language", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A register in the microprocessor that keeps track of the answer or results of any arithmetic or logic operation is the:", "opta": "stack pointer", "optb": "program counter", "optc": "instruction pointer", "optd": "accumulator", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the difference between a mnemonic code and machine code?", "opta": "There is no difference.", "optb": "Machine codes are in binary, mnemonic codes are in shorthand English.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which bus is a bidirectional bus?", "opta": "address bus", "optb": "data bus", "optc": "address bus and data bus", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following buses is primarily used to carry signals that direct other ICs to find out what type of operation is being performed?", "opta": "data bus", "optb": "control bus", "optc": "address bus", "optd": "address decoder bus", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What kind of computer program is used to convert mnemonic code to machine code?", "opta": "debug", "optb": "assembler", "optc": "C++", "optd": "Fortran", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following are the three basic sections of a microprocessor unit?", "opta": "operand, register, and arithmetic/logic unit (ALU)", "optb": "control and timing, register, and arithmetic/logic unit (ALU)", "optc": "control and timing, register, and memory", "optd": "arithmetic/logic unit (ALU), memory, and input/output", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}